Guide to the Time Inc. Comptroller Records 1957-1982 MS 3009-RG 37
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Comptroller Records
1957-1982
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 37
6 Linear feet in 7 record cartons
A collection of material produced during the comptroller's duties of supervising accounting and financial reporting. Includes material on accounting procedures and codes, accounts payable and receivable, balance sheets, lease agreements, and other financial information.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include contracts and are stored in box R86.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series: Series I. Finance Control Files; Series II. Accounting Services Ledgers on Fortune; and Series III. Accounting Classifications.
Historical Note
A comptroller is an executive responsible for supervising accounting and financial reporting. At Time Inc. the comptroller sat on the board as a vice-president. In the date range represented by this collection, the following people served as Time Inc.'s comptroller: Arnold Carlson until 1960; John F. Harvey from 1961 to 1971; David H. Dolben from 1971 to 1974; William E. Bishop from 1974 to 1978; and Kevin L. Dolan from 1978 to 1984, past the end of the dates represented in this collection.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. A folder pertaining to the comptroller's department can also be found in the Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence largely involving Comptrollers or Assistant Comptrollers, data on lease payments for offices, documents on accounting procedures, accounts payable and receivable, inventory counts, ledgers, balance sheets and other financial information, and a list of classifications for accounting codes.
Account books.; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I: Finance Control Files, 1957-1982
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains materials produced by the Finance Control division of the Comptroller's department and contains correspondence largely involving Comptrollers or Assistant Comptrollers, spreadsheets, data on lease payments for offices, meeting agenda, expenditure summaries, inventory counts, financial statements, balance sheets and other financial documents, and invoices.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically. Arrangement was imposed.
  - Advertising Rates, 1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 1)
  - Advertising Revenue Test: Time Magazine, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 2)
  - American Book-Stratford Press, 1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 3)
  - American Television and Communications (ATC) Contracts [Restricted], 1973 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Audits of Procedures, 1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 4)
  - Book and Record Reserve Test and Adjustments, 1975 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 5)
  - BRASS Reports, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 6)
  - Budgets and Re-estimates, 1975 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 7)
  - Business, Costs and Complaints Fulfillment, 1976 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 8)
  - Chicago (541): Cost Study, 1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 9)
  - Chicago (541): Cost System, 1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Cost Study (Barbara Corrigan), 1973 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Financial Review, 1976 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 12)
  - Chicago Memorandum, 1975 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 13)
  - Chicago Reserve Study, 1975 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 14)
  - Destruction of Old Accounting Records, 1978 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 15)
  - Domestic Inventory: Records, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 16)
  - Ernst & Ernst, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 17)
  - Form 10K: Sterling Communications, 1973 (Offsite-box 4152, Folder 18)
  - Form S-1: Time Incorporated, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 1)
  - Form S-8: Time Incorporated, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 2)
  - Form S-14: Time Incorporated, 1973 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 3)
  - General Learning Corporation [Restricted], 1974 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Haverhill's Chicago Processing Financial Control Report, 1973 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 4)
  - Home Box Office (HBO), 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 5)
  - Home Box Office (HBO): Columbia Pictures: Terms of Payment Verification, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 6)
  - Home Box Office (HBO): Earth Stations, 1976 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 7)
  - Home Box Office (HBO): Film Audit, 1977 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 8)
  - Home Box Office (HBO): Payments to Film Suppliers, 1976 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 9)
  - Home Box Office (HBO) Studio, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 10)
  - Home Box Office (HBO) Subscriber Information/Log/Program Guide/Miscellaneous, 1976 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 11)
  - Home Box Office (HBO): United Artists: Terms of Payment Verification, 1974 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 12)
  - Home Box Office: Deferred Expense, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 13)
  - Kingsport Press Physical Inventory Count, 1975 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 14)
  - Lease Disclosure Financing Leases Interest Expense, 1975 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 15)
  - Lease Disclosure Summary Sheets, 1973 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 16)
  - Lease Memo, 1975 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 17)
  - Leases, undated (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 18)
  - Little, Brown, 1976 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 19)
  - Little, Brown Intercompany Profits and Inventory, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 20-21)
  - Luberman's, 1973 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 22)
  - Lumbermen's Investment Corporation, 1972 (Offsite-box 4153, Folder 23)
  - New Building: Services [Restricted], 1961 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Mexico: A/R Analysis, 1974 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Publishers and Paper Product Companies Annual Reports and 10Ks, 1972-1974 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 2)
  - Morgan & Morgan, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 3)
  - New Buildings: Services, 1960-1964 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 4)
  - Occupancy Cost Allocations, 1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 5)
  - People Magazine: Loews Corp, 1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 6)
  - R.R. Donnelley & Sons: Physical Inventory Count, 1977 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 7)
  - Representative Agreement [Restricted], 1973 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Reports from Budgets, Re-Estimates, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 8-9)
  - Rock-Time Building, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 10)
  - Rock-Time Building [Restricted], 1957 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Rock-Time, Inc., 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 11)
  - Rock-Time Lease, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 12)
  - Rock-Time Leases: General, 1970-1974 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 13)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0001: Base Lease, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 14)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0009: 15th and 16th Floors, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 15)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0012: 11th, 37th, Sub-basement Mezzanine, 1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 16)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0115: 39th Floor, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 17)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0020: Sub-basement and Sub-basement Mezzanine, 1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 18)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0102: 14th Floor and Sub-basement, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 19)
  - Rock-Time Lease #15-0147: Sub-basement and Basement Mezzanine, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 20)
  - Rule of 78, 1975 (Offsite-box 4154, Folder 21)
  - Select Magazine Contract [Restricted], 1970 (Offsite-box R86)
  - St. Regis Paper Costs, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 1)
  - Study of Magazine Bad Pay, 1975 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 2)
  - Sublet Rental Operations, 1975 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 3)
  - Subscription Accounting and Books Division Product Control, 1973 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 4)
  - Subscription Income Report Summary, 1976 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 5)
  - Subscription Income Reports, 1973 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 6)
  - Temple Industries, Inc., 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 7)
  - Temple Industries, Inc. Schedules, 1973 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 8)
  - Time, 1975 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 9)
  - Time Issues: Geographic Differences, 1974 (Offsite-box 4155, Folder 10)
  - Time Issues: Geographic Differences, 1974 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 1)
  - Time Inc.: Non-Advertising Receivables Broadcast and Cable Audit, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 2)
  - Time Inc.: Non-Advertising Receivables Test, 1974 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 3)
  - Time Incorporated and Subsidiaries: Cash and Securities Reports, 1975 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 4)
  - Time Life Building: New York Lease Disclosures, 1975 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 5)
  - Time Life Libraries Inc. (T.L.L.I.): Telephone Book Sales, 1975 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 6)
  - Time Sharing Consolidating Balance Sheet Format, 1974 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 7)
  - Time and Life Building, SEC Filing, 1973 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 8)
  - Time: Latin America Newstand, undated (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 9)
  - Video: Home Box Office (HBO), 1973 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 10)
  - W.A. Krueger Physical Inventory Count, 1975 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 11)
  - Year-End Inventory Counts, 1975 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 12)
- Series II: Accounting Services Ledgers on Fortune, 1980-1982
  Series II consists of ledgers for Fortune magazine produced by the Accounting Services division of the Comptroller's department. The ledgers record income and expenditures by categories with comparisons between budgeted and actual amounts.
  Series II is arranged alphabetically. Arrangement was imposed.
  - Fortune General Ledger Distribution Register 1980 Review Adjusted (Offsite-box 4157, Item 1)
  - Fortune General Ledger Distribution Register 1981 Review Adjusted (Offsite-box 4157, Item 2)
  - Fortune General Ledger Distribution Register, 1981 (Offsite-box 4157, Item 3)
  - Fortune General Ledger Distribution Register January-June 1982 Review Adjusted (Offsite-box 4158, Item 1)
  - Fortune General Ledger Distribution for Rev/Adj September 1982 (Offsite-box 4158, Item 2)
  - Fortune General Ledger Distribution for Rev/Adj November 1982 (Offsite-box 4158, Item 3)
- Series III. Accounting Classifications, 1965-1972
  Series III consists of listings of classification codes referring to departments and personnel of Time Inc. and outside companies which were used in accounting processes.
  Series III is arranged alphabetically. Arrangement was imposed.
  - Account Codes, 1968, 1971 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 13)
  - Time Incorporated Account Classification, 1965 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 14)
  - Time Inc. Identification Number Listing, 1972 (Offsite-box 4156, Folder 15)